Finally, after a few years, we have new
investment funds under GCash GI Invest.
Specifically, we have four new unit
investment trust funds or UITFS. And
these are brought to us by Manual Life.
And the great thing about these funds is
that they are actually all dividend
paying. So, if you want some regular
income from your investments, these
funds might be for you. In today's
video, I'm sharing with you the details
on these four new funds, and I'm ranking
these funds from least interesting to
most interesting. Will they be worth
your time? This is what we'll look to
cover in this video. So, if you're
interested, stick around and let's find
out. Let's go. But before anything, if
you are new to this channel, hi, I'm
Mark. It's nice to meet you. In this
channel, I talk a little bit about
lifestyle, but I mostly talk about
business and investments. At long last,
we finally have new things that we can
invest in under G funds. As mentioned in
a few videos ago, Maya Funds from
G-Cash's main competitor has actually
caught up even as G-Cash was really
first to the scene in launching these
investment funds. So, I'm really glad
that GCash has these new investment
funds. Unfortunately though, Maya's main
feature of being able to show us easily
our return of investment, what we've
invested, and what's its current value.
This feature is still lacking in G fund.
So, G funds, I hope you hear this and
make it easier for a lot of us to be
able to track our investments. But
anyway, before going into these funds, I
wanted to give credit where credit is
due. And I like the fact that GF funds
has integrated these new funds into the
G fund section quite seamlessly. I mean
the main difference of Maya funds is
that their Maya funds actually branches
out into two sections between Seedbox
Philippines and Investors.
So the user interface, the way that Gund
has gone about this is cleaner, is a
little bit more easy to follow and I
applaud them for that.
So, let's now go into these four new
investment funds brought to us by Manual
Life. Again, I'm ranking these from
what's least interesting to me to the
most interesting one. Again, these four
funds are all dividend paying. So, it's
just about us finding the right
investment fund that fits your
investment goals and what you really
want out of it. Whether you want more
capital appreciation in terms of its net
asset value or maybe in terms of its
regular dividends. So these are the two
things that we're looking at today. So
just a disclaimer that I'm ranking these
based only on my own personal opinion.
So my opinions would again be fitting my
own investment goals. So let's start off
with number four. The least interesting
fund to me would be the Asia Dynamic
Bond Federer Fund. Now as a bond fund,
the criteria for investing in this would
be an aggressive risk tolerance. But
despite this aggressiveness, I would say
this is the most conservative one from
these four new funds. So, as always,
when it comes to stocks versus bonds,
bonds would always be on the
conservative side. So, it's investing in
Asian bonds that are either corporate or
governmentbacked. So, these are fixed
income securities, treasuries. Let's now
go into the historical performance of
this fund based on its key information
and investment disclosure. You may find
this in the manual life website. So in
terms of dividends in the last 12
months, the dividends that were paid out
by this fund totals 3.33%.
So the dividend for this fund is paid
out monthly. Moving on to its net asset
value. In the last 3 years, it is said
to have an annualized performance of
3.05%.
By the way, the data on the document is
as of June 30, 2025th. When we check the
G fund section, this actually displays
the performance of the fund in the last
1 year. And in this last 1-year period,
the fund is down unfortunately by a
negative 0.64%.
So with these numbers, you see why it is
the least interesting to me. I mean,
it's not really giving much in terms of
dividends. At the same time, it's also
not giving much in terms of capital
appreciation, in terms of its NAV. Let's
now move on to number three or the
second least interesting fund to me. So
for number three we have the manual life
global refeeder fund. So this is
actually one of two REIT feeder funds
that are being launched by G funds with
manual life. 70% of this fund is
invested in REITs or real estate
investment trusts while the remaining
30% would be invested in real estate
securities. As with the last fund, this
is also a monthly dividend payout. Its
returns in terms of dividends in the
last year equals 4.01%.
So this is slightly higher than our
previous fund. In terms of its net asset
value in the last 3 years, this has an
annualized performance of 2.37%.
So its capital appreciation is actually
very slow. While in the last 1-year
period, again based on the GCash G
invest section, its returns are at a
negative 2.07%.
Now between rank number three and number
four your opinion might actually vary. I
mean the Asia dynamic bond feeder fund
has slightly lower dividends but at the
same time the performance of the nav of
this global reap feeder fund is even
lower than the bond fund. Which one is
better? That might actually be
debatable. Let me know what you think in
the comment section. Let's now move on
to the second most interesting fund from
manual life. I mentioned earlier that
there are two refeeder funds that are
being launched and this would be the
second of them. This is the Asia-Pacific
REIT feeder fund. So specific for this
fund and this fund only. Unfortunately,
I wasn't able to find the key
information and investment disclosure
that Manual Life has on its website for
the other funds. They have a different
sort of layout, a different brochure for
this. So the data here is not completely
apples to apples. But anyway, this is
the best that I could abstract from what
they have on their website. So for its
dividend payouts, it's said to have
given out 4.46% 46% in the last 2 years.
This is already higher than our first
two funds. While in terms of its net
asset value, rather than just working
with a 3-year period, what I was able to
get is its 10-year annualized
performance. And this stands at 3.53%.
So, actually not bad. Again, this is
better performing than our first two
funds. And in the last one-year period,
according to the G fund section, the
fund has a return of 4.26%.
Now the main difference of this fund
from the other manual life funds being
launched is that its dividend payout is
only coming on a semiannual basis. So
this is only twice a year rather than
the monthly dividend payouts that the
other funds are doing. But in terms of
returns it's actually quite encouraging.
So again at number two that's the
Asia-Pacific REIT fund of funds. Let's
now move on to number one. What I think
is the most interesting of these manual
life funds. At number one we have the
manual life global preferred income
feeder fund. Now for the majority of its
portfolio over 70% is actually invested
in preferred securities. So these
preferred securities are invested in a
wide range of different industries.
Electric, banking, energy. So amongst
all these funds, this is perhaps the
most diverse, perhaps also the most
volatile. But based on data, it's
looking like it's giving the best
returns. In the last 12 months, the
total dividends that have been paid out
is at 5.01%.
While in terms of its net asset value in
the last 3 years, the global preferred
income feeder fund has an annualized
return of 7.48%.
While in the last 1-year period, again
based on the G fund section, this fund
has a return of just 0.8%.
So, those are the four new funds that
are being launched under G funds by
Manual Life. All of these funds have a
minimum of 1,000 pesos to get started.
while the trust fee everything is at
1.75%
except for the bond fund. The bond fund
actually comes in at 1.5%. So that's how
I would be ranking these funds. Well, as
always, I would actually like to invest
in these funds. I am getting started in
investing in them. Unfortunately, it's
quite pricey, but as with most
investments in this channel, I actually
like to try it out, see the actual
results, and compare this to what's
printed in the disclosure forms. Again,
since GF funds has no way to be able to
track additional investments, for now,
I'm just going to be investing the
minimum, and I'm going to be reporting
that to you in future videos how it's
fairing. Some of you have said that the
monthly dividends aren't coming in. So,
I actually wanted to try it out, see
what the situation is on these
dividends. So, as mentioned previously,
the ALFM global multiasset income fund
like one of you have said in the comment
section, these types of dividend paying
funds will not really be your engine
towards retirement. It's not really
going to be about capital appreciation.
It definitely helps with cash flow, but
it's not going to be performing
alongside the S&P 500 or other equities.
Again, dividend paying funds are there
to do exactly what is said to be paying
you regular dividends and the net asset
value will always be tempered because
you are really looking at the dividends
first and foremost. So with this, how
does it compare? Well, I think the ALFM
global multi-asset income fund still has
performed better. I mean the dividends
for the ALFM fund is at 5.97% in the
last 1-year period while its net asset
value performance in the last 3 years is
at an annualized value of 6.56%.
So again yes the famous or infamous ALFM
global multiasset income fund while
loved and hated by a lot of you
historically speaking is performing
better than these manual life funds.
This is not a paid advertisement. I
mean, I've done a lot of videos on the
ALFM Global Multi-Asset Income Fund, not
because I'm paid, but only because you
guys like to talk about it and it gets a
lot of views. So, it does help me keep
this channel afloat. But just calling it
as it is, maybe this will not be the
case in the future, especially this fund
is again aggressively investing in
global REITs and preferred securities
across different industries. So, these
funds might just be looking up in terms
of their performance. So, what do you
think about these manuli funds? Do you
think it's worthwhile? Are you attracted
by their dividends? If you like this
video, please don't forget to like,
comment, and consider subscribing if you
haven't already. Thanks again for
watching, guys, and happy investing.